Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
It is the year 0079 of the Universal Century.
The colonies of Side 3 proclaimed themselves
the Principality of Zeon.
It launched a war of independence
against the Earth Federation.
During this war, the Principality of Zeon
and the Federation...
...caused the deaths
of half the total population.
Humanity was horrified by its own actions.
Icelina - Love's Remains
Beyond the moon...
...deep in outer space,
at the furthest distance from Earth...
...float dozens of space colonies.
This is the Principality of Zeon,
a nation of space colonies ruled by the Zabi family...
...who seek to impose their dictatorship
upon all of the Earth.
Within these giant cylindrical structures
floating in space...
...there is a world in which people live.
These cylinders are
approximately 6 km in diameter...
...and over 30 km in length.
An artificial living environment
has been created within...
...where people are able to live
as though they were on Earth.
Right now, the commander of
Zeon's Space Attack Force...
...Vice Admiral Dozle Zabi...
...has just returned
from his frontline base.
Nothing's changed in six months.
No new fortifications have been built.
Space colonies use centrifugal force
to generate gravity, and as a result...
...people live along the inner wall
of the cylindrical capsule.
This is Zum City, the capital
of the Principality of Zeon.
We cannot let Garma's death be in vain.
The honor of the Zabi family is at stake.
Gihren, I just want Garma's death to be...
Excuse my interruption.
Lord Dozle Zabi and Lady Kycilia Zabi...
...have presently arrived from the frontlines.
Let them in.
Father!
You two made it quickly.
Father! You must be...
It is regrettable that Garma should fall
before the Federation's mobile suit.
Big brother, I still can't believe it.
I keep thinking he'll show up any minute.
You won't win any battles
by dwelling on the past, Dozle.
But...
...I was looking forward
to him becoming a general...
...who'd be giving me orders.
It's just as Dozle says.
That's why, Gihren...
...we must pray for the peaceful repose
of Garma's soul...
...in a quiet and respectful manner.
Sorry to keep you waiting, Miss Icelina.
Miss Icelina...
I was watching you from a distance
at that last party.
That is, I mean...
...all the officers present were praising
your beauty and grace, Miss Icelina.
This is the room that was
used by Lord Garma.
This must surely be a time
of great sorrow for you.
But we will not let them go unpunished.
Miss Icelina, we will absolutely...
Lieutenant Darota...
Yes, ma'am!
Please let me aboard the Gaw.
Miss Icelina?!
The vile enemy who killed my Garma...
The least I can do
is exact revenge upon them.
But... that would be...
Lieutenant Darota...!
Isn't it a bit early for that?
We've come this far. We're as good as there.
I hear that the Federation Forces
are coming to pick us up.
We're impatient! it'll be first-come,
first-served as soon as we land!
We've hit some powerful turbulence.
What is that?
Maybe an air pocket?
We have hit turbulence.
It'll get rough for a while, but don't worry.
Did you figure it out?
Yes.
The built-in safety valve prevented it
from extending into the javelin.
I see! It looks like you're
pretty well-suited for engineering.
You think so?
All right!
Can you use both as javelins?
Of course! They're both the same!
Enemy aircraft sighted at 11 o'clock!
A formation of three!
Laser analysis... They're Gaws!
Three Gaws approaching!
Amuro! Ryu!
Is Gundam maintenance finished?
Yeah, we can launch anytime!
The engines aren't performing well.
Bright. How about an emergency landing?
We're just a stone's throw away
from reaching Federation airspace.
Rescuers could be on their way.
Mr. Bright, the White Base should
stay headed for Federation airspace.
You'll get caught in the turbulence.
Actually, It'll help me dodge a direct hit.
Amuro, we're going to jump to that spot!
Can you do It?!
I...I'll try!
They're coming! Fire on the mobile suits!
Mobile suits!
They're responsible for Garma's...!
We will avenge Captain Garma's death
no matter what, Miss Icelina.
Fire! Fire! Shoot them down!
Mr. Ryu! It's more powerful
because we're so close to it!
We just have to destroy the gun turrets!
Number 2, cover Number 3!
I-Idiots!
D-Damn mobile suits!
Don't you have any fighter planes?!
Unfortunately, after the last few battles...
...the number of combat-ready planes is...
What's that?!
This is Char. I'll give you a hand.
Lt. Commander Char, it's me!
Lieutenant Darota, formerly under
Captain Garma's direct command!
I don't care who you are.
Aim for the cockpit.
The cockpit, sir?
The belly. It's the heart of the Gundam.
Yes, sir!
I will attack the Trojan Horse.
We're going to finish them off for good now.
Taking responsibility for Garma's death...
Showing loyalty
to Vice Admiral Dozle...
Either way, I can't lose.
A message from the Federation Forces.
What?!
The liaison conference at General HQ
is still in deadlock?!
It looks like we can't expect reinforcements.
After all, even Matilda's Medea helping us
has become an issue.
Why?
Don't they care what happens to us?
There's more to the message.
"Preparing to take on refugees."
"Head for point S-109, N-23."
Mirai! Change course, 1.5 degrees!
Yes, sir!
Enemy aircraft at 10 o'clock!
Here it comes!
The safety's on!
We've been hit! Port-side rear!
It's no good! I can't switch over the power!
We've lost control.
Mobile Suit
Emergency landing!
Hang on to something, everyone!
Buckle your seat belts if you can!
Landing now!
There must be an easy way
to capture the Trojan Horse.
Mirai. You did well.
It wasn't due to my abilities.
It's thanks to the White Base's performance.
You're too modest.
Are you all right, Ms. Sayla?
Yes.
Could you please go check on the refugees?
Are you all right?!
Yeah, for the most part!
Let's drop down for a while!
Roger!
Please don't let them get away!
And please make sure you destroy them!
Emergency repairs to the power section are
complete, so we should be able to manage.
Good.
Power section, are you ready?
Yes. Power output is down 25%
but It should be okay.
All okay over here. No problems.
The White Base sure is
amazingly well-built.
All right. Now we just have to
get out of here, fast.
If we're hit, we won't be able to move.
Shall I contact Amuro and Ryu?
Have we received any emergency signals?
No, I haven't caught any signs
of malfunctions yet, either.
Bright! Bright!
Several of the refugees have
left the ship without permission!
What?!
No, we can't stand this anymore!
Stop! Don't do it!
Come back, come back!
Getting off here is too dangerous!
Please, don't do it...
Return now! It's not safe!
The enemy may be near!
You have to come back, quickly!
The Zeons are after the White Base
and the Gundam.
This has nothing to do with us.
That's right. We're only in danger
because we're on the White Base.
Let me out of here!
What do you plan to do in a desert like this?
Why, that's...!
What's wrong with mourning Garma
just within our royal family?
Father, we're at war right now.
In order to strengthen
the fighting spirit of our people...
...there can be nothing more
appropriate than a state funeral.
Garma's death does not concern him alone.
It concerns the entire Principality of Zeon.
I agree with Gihren.
More importantly, we must deal with Char.
Punishing the one who failed
to protect Garma...
...will serve as an example to the people.
Well, you can deal with that
on your own authority.
The important thing is
the funeral ceremony, Father.
Garma was very popular among the people.
Having a state funeral for him...
...will help stir up the people's hatred
toward the Federation.
Wouldn't that be a vital thing to do now?
Father...
As far as Char is concerned...
...Dozle, have him demoted.
Father...!
As sovereign of the Principality of Zeon,
please make your decision now!
Cover me, Mr. Ryu!
Okay!
Now! Concentrate all fire on the mobile suit!
Good! Just a little more!
Amuro!
Don't falter! Shoot down the mobile suit!
My shield's giving way!
That's Hayato! All right, Gaw...
Here I come!
H-Hey!
Darota!
My arm! I can't pilot!
I'll take over!
Miss Icelina!
It wouldn't be fair to Garma
if we didn't do anything.
It's still coming at us...?
I-It's still coming at us...?!
Mobile suit! I will avenge Garma!
Oh no! One of the circuits was damaged!
Amuro! Are you all right?! Amuro?!
Mr. Bright, the Gundam is malfunctioning.
I'll go inspect it.
All right. There may be soldiers
in the Gaw. Be careful.
Yes, sir!
Lieutenant Darota!
Lieutenant!
Vengeance for Garma...
Did... Did she say vengeance?
Me...? Vengeance on me...?
It seems you can't rely on others.
Dren. We'll report that my mobile suit...
...wasn't working because
the electrical systems were all burned out.
We're rescued!
I wonder what her name was?
She said she wanted vengeance on me.
Amuro is exhausted.
But a new enemy, Ramba Ral,
descends upon him.
The massive destructive power
of a new enemy mobile suit...
...easily overwhelms the Gundam.
And the cry of "Sieg Zeon!" is heard by all.
Mobile Suit Gundam.
Next episode...
The Threat of Zeon!
Will you be able to survive?
Next Time
The Threat of Zeon
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...